# **Philip Tomlinson**

Freelance Web Developer



#### **SUMMARY**

I'm a **freelance web developer** providing professional services for clients and agencies throughout the UK. I work with clients of all shapes and sizes, from start-ups and small business to large national companies.

With 20 years of experience in the industry, I've worked with many languages and frameworks, from basic HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript, to Blazor, Jekyll, WordPress, and many more.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Freelance Web Developer

Coderover Ltd [2013 - present]

Provide web development services on a freelance basis for a wide range of clients. Use a multitude of languages and frameworks to fit client requirements and needs, as listed in my current **SKILLS**.

## **Head of Development**

First Internet Marketing [2007 - 2013]

Worked as a full-stack developer primarily with PHP and MySQL. Frameworks included CakePHP, WordPress, and Magento. Managed a small team of developers to deliver projects to clients.

## IT Manager

Prestbury Travel Group [2005 - 2007]

Maintained company website for hotels and villas. Developed internal customer quotation application using PHP and MySQL. Provided general IT support for staff members across several locations.

# Junior Developer

Purepages Group [2004 - 2005]

Built and maintainted internal and external website applications using ASP, PHP, and MySQL. Tested internal software applications developed externally.

### **EDUCATION**

BEng (Hon) Software Engineering
University of Bradford [2001 - 2004]

## **SKILLS**

- ✓ HTML5
- ✓ JavaScript
- ✓ CSS
- ✓ Sass
- ✔ Bootstrap
- ✓ Blazor
- ✔ Jekyll
- ✔ WordPress
- ✓ Git
- ✓ Gulp
- ✓ Linux CLI

#### RATE

Negotiable

## CONTACT

Email phil@coderover.co.uk

Telephone +44 7921 822977

Website www.coderover.co.uk